A Guide to the McCue Family Papers ca. 1767-1944
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: McCue Family Papers (Box 1-18)
  - Correspondence
    - Drinker & Morris 1845 (Box 3)
    - R.T.W. Duke 1870-1872 (Box 3)
    - J.N. Dunlap 1860 (Box 3)
    - A.N. Dunnavant 1871 (Box 3)
    - R.T. Durrett 1887 (Box 3)
    - Marvin Eastwood 1870 (Box 3)
    - Edward Echols 1881 (Box 3)
    - John Echols 1854 (Box 3)
    - Charles Edwards 1877 (Box 3)
    - May J. Elbridge 1855 (Box 3)
    - Richard S. Ellis 1857 (Box 3)
    - Elmington Military and Classical School 1872-1874 (Box 3)
    - H.H. Emerson 1881 (Box 3)
    - Richard Eppes 1877 (Box 3)
    - William S. Eskridge 1858 (Box 3)
    - William H. Estes 1851 (Box 3)
    - John N. Eubank 1850 (Box 3)
    - Thomas J. Evans 1883, 1887 (Box 3)
    - John S. Ewers 1858 (Box 3)
    - Stephen R. Ewers 1849-1853 (Box 3)
    - Benjamin Estill 1853-1867 (Box 3)
    - Samuel Fahnestock 1849 (Box 3)
    - S.W. Farley 1846 (Box 3)
    - Amanda Farrow 1872 (Box 3)
    - George A. Farrow 1850 (Box 3)
    - Joseph Fauber 1860 (Box 3)
    - S.A. Ferguson 1854 (Box 3)
    - Samuel Finley 1804 (Box 3)
    - Daniel Fishburn 1854 (Box 3)
    - Frederick Fisher 1854 (Box 3)
    - Alexander Fitzpatrick 1849, 1853 (Box 3)
    - E.B. Fitzpatrick 1854 (Box 3)
    - M.H. Fitzpatrick 1850-1851 (Box 3)
    - Samuel Fitzpatrick 1852 (Box 3)
    - Thomas P. Fitzpatrick 1870-1874 (Box 3)
    - B.C. Flannagan 1854 (Box 3)
    - William M. Flannagan 1885-1886 (Box 3)
    - I.J. Fleming n.d. (Box 3)
    - J.T. Forbes 1844 (Box 3)
    - W.W. Forbes 1869-1870 (Box 3)
    - A.A. Foster 1867 (Box 3)
    - John A. Foster 1854, 1870 (Box 3)
    - Fowle & Company 1860 (Box 3)
    - William Frazier 1850-1870 (Box 3)
    - C.F. Fry 1859 (Box 3)
    - C.G. Fulks 1868 (Box 3)
    - John C. Fuller 1854 (Box 3)
    - David Fultz 1851-1875 (Box 3)
    - Ficklin, Flannagan & Company 1853 (Box 3)
    - Dr. James A. Forbes 1845-1870 (Box 3)
    - E.P. Gaines 1871 (Box 3)
    - H.L. Gallager 1853 (Box 3)
    - A.J. Garber 1860 (Box 3)
    - Dr. Gardner n.d. (Box 3)
    - J. Garland 1861 (Box 3)
    - Samuel M. Garland 1859 (Box 3)
    - Ira Garrett 1858 (Box 3)
    - Thomas E. Garvin 1859 (Box 3)
    - W.W. Gibbs 1858-1859 (Box 3)
    - William J. Gibson, Jr. 1866-1867 (Box 3)
    - George R. Giles 1860 (Box 3)
    - Thomas Walker Gilmer 1837 (Box 3)
    - James H. Gilmore 1867 (Box 3)
    - Glasgox & Glasgow 1882 (Box 3)
    - A.C. Gleaves 1887 (Box 3)
    - John M. Godwin 1869-1870 (Box 3)
    - William L. Goggin 1849 (Box 3)
    - H.H. Gordon 1889 (Box 3)
    - John N. Gordon 1844 (Box 3)
    - Samuel J. Graham 1887 (Box 3)
    - O.W. Gray 1880 (Box 3)
    - G.W. Greiner 1850 (Box 3)
    - William Gurner 1860 (Box 3)
    - J. Emmet Guy 1872 (Box 3)
    - Robert Guy 1872 (Box 3)
    - George N. Gwathmey 1859-1860 (Box 3)
    - Minnie Rives Habersham 1878 (Box 3)
    - Alexander Hall 1857 (Box 3)
    - W.H. Hall 1860 (Box 3)
    - A. Halsey 1849 (Box 3)
    - Edwin S. Halsey 1858 (Box 3)
    - Joseph J. Halsey 1854 (Box 3)
    - Seth Halsey 1845-1867 (Box 3)
    - Virginia B. Hamilton 1884 (Box 3)
    - John D. Hammerley for J.A. Cowardin, Richmond Dispatch1858 (Box 3)
    - Robert M. Hamner 1874 (Box 3)
    - Marshall Hanger 1870 (Box 3)
    - William W. Hardwicke 1867 (Box 3)
    - Harmon & Bell 1859-1860 (Box 3)
    - Colonel A.W. Harmon 1876 (Box 3)
    - J.R. Harmon 1869-1872 (Box 3)
    - M.G. Harmon 1859, 1866 (Box 3)
    - W.M. Harnest 1849 (Box 3)
    - C.R. Harris 1850, 1858 (Box 3)
    - Cassie K. Harris 1876 (Box 3)
    - Fannie Harris 1878 (Box 3)
    - Hugh Harris 1871 (Box 3)
    - John S. Harris 1874 (Box 3)
    - John W. Harris 1877, 1884 (Box 3)
    - Thomas T. Harris 1853 (Box 3)
    - W.W.H. Harris 1876 (Box 3)
    - Hartman & Straus 1867 (Box 3)
    - James E. Heath 1851 (Box 3)
    - Decatur Hedges 1874 (Box 3)
    - J.W. & R. Henley 1869 (Box 3)
    - Henley & Hargrove 1859 (Box 3)
    - S.H. Henry 1871 (Box 3)
    - Hester & Darneille 1869 (Box 3)
    - James M. Hight 1860 (Box 3)
    - Robert Hill 1861 (Box 3)
    - S.H. Hill 1860 (Box 3)
    - W.J. Hilton 1879 (Box 3)
    - John F. Hix 1873 (Box 3)
    - W. Hix 1853-1854 (Box 3)
    - John Hodsly 1873 (Box 3)
    - J.B. Hogshead 1858 (Box 3)
    - P.B. Hoge & Brother 1870-1872 (Box 3)
    - Anthony Hopkins 1846, 1852-1857 (Box 3)
    - William J. Hopkins 1850, 1860 (Box 3)
    - Joseph F. Hottel 1851 (Box 3)
    - Dr. Howard 1851 (Box 3)
    - V.V. Howard 1870 (Box 3)
    - R.R. Howison 1859 (Box 3)
    - James L. Hubard 1870-1874, 1887 (Box 3)
    - John A. Hudson 1874 (Box 3)
    - Robert Hull 1868-1869 (Box 3)
    - Samuel Hunter 1857 (Box 3)
    - A.E. Hupp 1857 (Box 3)
    - Don P. Halsey 1866-1878 (Box 3)
    - Jedediah Hotchkiss 1857-1872 (Box 3)
    - Daniel Harmon 1869-1871 (Box 3)
    - F.M. Imboden 1869-1870, 1886 (Box 4)
    - Henry Imboden 1840 (Box 4)
    - Edward Irvine 1854 (Box 4)
    - William E. Isbell 1871 (Box 4)
    - W.C. Ivey 1870 (Box 4)
    - George Imboden 1858-1861 (Box 4)
    - John D. Imboden 1847-1889, n.d., 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Tillotson Janney 1856 (Box 4)
    - George C. Jackson 1874 (Box 4)
    - Thomas Jackson 1870 (Box 4)
    - E.E. Jefferson 1859 (Box 4)
    - Burge Johnson 1849 (Box 4)
    - Charles Johnson 1860 (Box 4)
    - C. Johnson 1837 (Box 4)
    - George N. Johnson 1839 (Box 4)
    - George T. Johnson 1870 (Box 4)
    - George Jones 1859-1860 (Box 4)
    - Henry B. Jones 1857 (Box 4)
    - Davis A. Kayser 1853, 1870 (Box 4)
    - James Lawson Kemper 1868-1887 (Box 4)
    - Samuel Kennerley 1876 (Box 4)
    - Kent, Paine, & Company 1857 (Box 4)
    - H.M. Keran 1869 (Box 4)
    - William M. Keran 1859-1860 (Box 4)
    - C. Kidd 1867 (Box 4)
    - John E. King 1857 (Box 4)
    - G.M. King n.y. November 17 (Box 4)
    - W.W. King 1859 (Box 4)
    - Asa Kinne 1847 (Box 4)
    - Nicholas C. Kinney 1845 (Box 4)
    - B.W. Knowles 1854 (Box 4)
    - P.K. Kurtz 1869 (Box 4)
    - Joseph L.S. Kirby 1870-1893 (Box 4)
    - James C. Laird 1854 (Box 4)
    - B.B. Lapham 1852-1853 (Box 4)
    - Larew & Lewis 1880 (Box 4)
    - J. Lauberman 1854 (Box 4)
    - Martha Lawton 1874 (Box 4)
    - Nina Lea 1856 (Box 4)
    - Shelton F. Leake 1860 (Box 4)
    - John Leonard 1870 (Box 4)
    - Lee & Hughes 1870 (Box 4)
    - A.S. Lee 1859, 1866 (Box 4)
    - E. Lee 1854 (Box 4)
    - P. LeNeve 1852-1853 (Box 4)
    - John Letcher 1850-1851 (Box 4)
    - W.H. Letcher 1869 (Box 4)
    - Levering & Brothers 1851 (Box 4)
    - Lewis & Alderson 1847 (Box 4)
    - David Lewis 1800 (Box 4)
    - Senator John Francis Lewis 1872 (Box 4)
    - C.B. Lipscomb 1872 (Box 4)
    - John Livingston 1859 (Box 4)
    - J.A. Logan 1875-1876 (Box 4)
    - N.L. Looke 1869 (Box 4)
    - Loving & Pierce 1870-1871 (Box 4)
    - C.M. Loving 1853-1854 (Box 4)
    - Henry Loving 1849 (Box 4)
    - L. Loving 1868 (Box 4)
    - O. Loving 1853 (Box 4)
    - Robbie Loving 1872 (Box 4)
    - S.H. Loving 1851, 1871 (Box 4)
    - F.E. Luckett 1853, 1861 (Box 4)
    - Harmon P. Lushbaugh 1860 (Box 4)
    - W.H.H. Lynn 1869 December 11 (Box 4)
    - Jennie C. Leebrick 1859-1861, 1868-1869 (Box 4)
    - Lynchburg Hose and Fire Insurance Company 1851-1858, n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Benjamin Martin 1877 (Box 5)
    - C.L. Martin 1871, 1883 (Box 5)
    - Garrett W. Martin 1873 (Box 5)
    - Hudson Martin 1860-1861 (Box 5)
    - J.H Martin and Martin & Cardozo 1866-1874 (Box 5)
    - Anna D. Mason 1854 (Box 5)
    - Miles F. Mason 1853-1854 (Box 5)
    - John E. Massey 1867 (Box 5)
    - N.H. Massie 1852, 1858 (Box 5)
    - Thomas J. Massie 1848-1868 (Box 5)
    - Felix Matthews 1858 (Box 5)
    - Harriet Matthews 1861 (Box 5)
    - Tyre Maupin 1852, 1854 (Box 5)
    - Matthew F. Maury 1870 (Box 5)
    - R.H. Maury & Company 1858 (Box 5)
    - Alexander Mays 1867 (Box 5)
    - Daniel Mays 1859 (Box 5)
    - Robert M. Mayo 1885-1888 (Box 5)
    - McAlexander & Patterson 1860 (Box 5)
    - F.A. McChesney 1854, 1871 (Box 5)
    - J. Bruce McClelland 1859-1860 (Box 5)
    - McCorkle & Company 1859 (Box 5)
    - McCormick & Henry 1859-1860 (Box 5)
    - McCue & Company 1872-1873 (Box 5)
    - Christian McDivett 1874 (Box 5)
    - McDonald & Moore 1886 (Box 5)
    - McDonald 1847-1850 (Box 5)
    - James M. McDowell 1850 (Box 5)
    - William McFee 1858 (Box 5)
    - C.P. McKennie 1846 (Box 5)
    - C.M. McLain 1883 (Box 5)
    - William McLaughlin 1853 (Box 5)
    - S.C.M. Merillat 1858 (Box 5)
    - B. Meyers 1873-1874 (Box 5)
    - Thomas J. Michie 1860 (Box 5)
    - W. Porcher Miles 1874 (Box 5)
    - J.W. Miller 1883 (Box 5)
    - Miller & Franklin, Bankers and Brokers 1874 (Box 5)
    - H.M. Moffet 1846-1847 (Box 5)
    - R.H. Moffet 1887 (Box 5)
    - James M. Montague 1874 (Box 5)
    - Robert L. Montague 1859 (Box 5)
    - James N. Montgomery 1845 (Box 5)
    - George W. Moore 1857 (Box 5)
    - Moorman & Martin 1850 (Box 5)
    - Morrison & Ray 1859 (Box 5)
    - A.D. Mosby 1869-1870 (Box 5)
    - W.H. Mosby 1871 (Box 5)
    - B.H. Mullikin 1858 (Box 5)
    - Charles Mundy 1874 (Box 5)
    - William B. Murrill 1861 (Box 5)
    - McCue Family 1806-1903, n.d., 3 folders (Box 5)
      Aurelia Halsey, Aurelia P. McCue, B. Taylor McCue, Don H. McCue, E.M. McCue, Elizabeth McCue, Eller S. McCue, H.B. McCue, Hannah McCue, [Irvin?] McCue, James McCue, Jr., James M. McCue, the Rev. John McCue, John Willis McCue, Lina Linn McCue, M.H. McCue, M.M. McCue, Martha McCue, Mattie J. McCue, Otelia McCue, Richard McCue, Thomas W. McCue, W.A. McCue, William McCue
    - C. Purcell McCue, Jr. 1939-1942 (Box 5)
    - John McCue 1848-1860 (Box 6)
    - John Howard McCue 1846-1887, n.d., 2 folders (Box 6)
    - John Marshall McCue 1849-1888, n.d., 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Signora (Wills) McCue 1845-1874, n.d. (Box 6)
    - William T. McCue 1897-1909 (Box 6)
    - James McDonald 1859-1887 (Box 6)
    - George B. Moffett 1850-1883 (Box 7)
    - James M.D. Moffett 1849-1853 (Box 7)
    - John G. Mosby and Others 1870-1872 (Box 7)
      re the Salary of Judge John Howard McCue
    - James E. Neale 1877 (Box 7)
    - Philip Nelson n.d. (Box 7)
    - A. Nicholas 1877 (Box 7)
    - P.E. Nilson 1878 (Box 7)
    - T.J. Obenchain 1867 (Box 7)
    - Peter J. Otey 1865 (Box 7)
    - John Newton 1851, 1858-1860 (Box 7)
    - P.A. Krise Banking House 1874 (Box 7)
    - P.A Sublett & Company 1872, 1874 (Box 7)
    - D.H. Page 1870 (Box 7)
    - S.M. Page 1844 (Box 7)
    - William M. Page 1871 (Box 7)
    - A.M. Pamplin 1872 (Box 7)
    - Royal Parrish 1847-1854 (Box 7)
    - Parrish & Beazley 1845 (Box 7)
    - Hy M. Patterson 1888 (Box 7)
    - Patterson & Bash 1869-1870 (Box 7)
    - Patterson & Cochran 1872-1874 (Box 7)
    - John Paul 1869 (Box 7)
    - William H. Payne 1872 (Box 7)
    - R.E. Pegram 1871 (Box 7)
    - Edmund Pendleton 1867 (Box 7)
    - William C. Pendleton 1887 (Box 7)
    - W.H. Perkins 1873-1877 (Box 7)
    - Charles Perrow 1849-1856 (Box 7)
    - D. Perrow 1850 (Box 7)
    - J.M. Perry 1892 (Box 7)
    - William F. Perry 1878 (Box 7)
    - Dr. A Peters 1870 (Box 7)
    - Annie Peters 1849-1850 (Box 7)
    - Don J.C. Peters 1846-1858 (Box 7)
    - Joseph M. Peters 1845 (Box 7)
    - S.T. Peters 1870 (Box 7)
    - W. Peterson 1867-1870 (Box 7)
    - Jesse M. Pettyjohn 1874 (Box 7)
    - Henrietta Peyton n.d. (Box 7)
    - G. Howe Peyton 1869-1870 (Box 7)
    - Joseph P. Phillips 1860 (Box 7)
    - Robert H. Phillips 1851-1874 (Box 7)
    - William B. Phillips 1872 (Box 7)
    - Phillips & Mayo 1870 (Box 7)
    - Matthew Pilson 1859 (Box 7)
    - James S. Piper 1857 (Box 7)
    - Piper & Funkhouser 1859-1860 (Box 7)
    - R. Plummer 1857 (Box 7)
    - J. Powell 1849 (Box 7)
    - John E. Powell 1870, 1874 (Box 7)
    - Leonard Powell 1859 (Box 7)
    - P. Powell 1868 (Box 7)
    - Powell & Company 1860 (Box 7)
    - R. Pollard 1872 (Box 7)
    - Pollard & Strattan 1870 (Box 7)
    - Dr. D.W. Prescott 1859 (Box 7)
    - J. Maxwell Pringle 1860 (Box 7)
    - E.F. Pruden 1859-1860 (Box 7)
    - Samuel H. Pulliam 1867 (Box 7)
    - Perkins & Ewer 1849-1852 (Box 7)
    - Frederick G. Peters 1846-1874 (Box 7)
    - J. Montgomery Peters 1846-1870 (Box 7)
    - S.T. Peters 1852-1872 (Box 7)
    - W.S. Peters 1849-1851 (Box 7)
    - William Elisha Peters 1849-1869 (Box 7)
    - Wilson Peters 1845-1861 (Box 7)
    - Peters, Martin & Company 1854-1858 (Box 7)
    - W.V. Randolph 1869 (Box 7)
    - Thomas D. Ranson 1870, 1874 (Box 7)
    - Samuel Read 1847-1860 (Box 7)
    - D. Reamer 1852 (Box 7)
    - A.A. Reese 1850 (Box 7)
    - J. Reid 1796 (Box 7)
    - Thomas Reitz 1861 (Box 7)
    - Aurelius Reynolds 1844 (Box 7)
    - John M. Roberts 1872 (Box 7)
    - H.H. Roberts 1871 (Box 7)
    - P.D. Roberts 1868-1869 (Box 7)
    - Pleasant Roberts 1870 (Box 7)
    - W.A. Roberts 1857 (Box 7)
    - A.F. Robertson 1861 (Box 7)
    - E.T. Robertson 1870 (Box 7)
    - H.H. Robertson 1872 (Box 7)
    - Judge John Robertson 1860-1861 (Box 7)
    - W.B. Robertson 1861, 1867 (Box 7)
    - William J. Robertson 1881 (Box 7)
    - William Robin 1867 (Box 7)
    - Rogers & Company 1869 (Box 7)
    - William H. Rose 1854, 1860 (Box 7)
    - J.A. Ross 1859 (Box 7)
    - J.R. Rudisill 1858 (Box 7)
    - John Rudisill 1858 (Box 7)
    - Rosa Russell 1881 (Box 7)
    - Alexander Rives and William Cabell Rives 1828, 1859-1874 (Box 7)
    - W.B. Roane 1845-1853 (Box 8)
    - William C. Roberts 1850-1867 (Box 8)
    - Leverett Saltonstall 1860 (Box 8)
    - C. Whittle Sams 1889 (Box 8)
    - Emma P. Saul 1872 (Box 8)
    - C.N. Scates 1858 (Box 8)
    - G.E. Schmucker 1876 (Box 8)
    - P. Schmucker 1849-1854 (Box 8)
    - G.G. Schoolfield 1847 (Box 8)
    - A.G. Scott 1859-1860 (Box 8)
    - P. Seabury 1869 (Box 8)
    - Joseph Sedgwick 1854-1856 (Box 8)
    - Robert B. Shalton 1870-1872 (Box 8)
    - Hugh W. Sheffey 1845-1870 (Box 8)
    - Joseph H. Shelton 1854-1874 (Box 8)
    - Paulina S. Shelton 1867 (Box 8)
    - J.C. Shields 1857-1860 (Box 8)
    - W.J. Shumate 1859, 1861 (Box 8)
    - A.K. Smith 1859 (Box 8)
    - C.D.F. Smith 1871 (Box 8)
    - James M. Smith 1867 (Box 8)
    - Joel T. Smith n.d. (Box 8)
    - J.M. Smithee 1860 (Box 8)
    - David Speck 1859-1860 (Box 8)
    - William B. Spooner 1853 (Box 8)
    - B.P. Spotts 18? (Box 8)
    - M.H. Spotts 1879 (Box 8)
    - James C. Southall 1860 (Box 8)
    - A.A. Steele 1852 (Box 8)
    - George S. Stevens 1860 (Box 8)
    - Lowell Stevenson 1867 (Box 8)
    - Joseph Stewart 1857 (Box 8)
    - T.G. Stout 1858 (Box 8)
    - L.D. Stratton 1871 (Box 8)
    - C.C. Strayer 1849-1853 (Box 8)
    - F.T. Stribling 1860, 1872 (Box 8)
    - J.W. Stribling 1860 (Box 8)
    - A.A. Stuart 1853 (Box 8)
    - Archibald Stuart n.d. (Box 8)
    - James T. Stuart 1845 (Box 8)
    - William Summerson n.d. (Box 8)
    - W.T. Sutherlin 1865 (Box 8)
    - Gabriel & Joseph Santini 1874-1887 (Box 8)
    - John B. Spiece 1854-1878 (Box 8)
    - M.B. Tate 1847, 1864 (Box 8)
    - Eliza Taylor 1875-1876, n.d. (Box 8)
    - Mark Taylor 1852 (Box 8)
    - W.F. Taylor 1871 (Box 8)
    - W.W. Taylor 1859 (Box 8)
    - William Robin Terry 1870 (Box 8)
    - W.N. Thacker 1868 (Box 8)
    - D.C. Thomas 1861, 1874 (Box 8)
    - G. Thomas 1843 (Box 8)
    - John M. Thomas 1866 (Box 8)
    - G.P. Thompson 1871 (Box 8)
    - John Thompson, Jr. 1849-1851 (Box 8)
    - John Thompson & Company 1844, 1846 (Box 8)
    - Lucas P. Thompson 1859-1860 (Box 8)
    - William B. Thompson 1877 (Box 8)
    - H.C. Thurmond 1887 (Box 8)
    - William M. Thurmond 1852 (Box 8)
    - Robert Tinsley 1849-1851 (Box 8)
    - Tinsley, Taylor and Company 1853 (Box 8)
    - G.W. Tompkins 1866 (Box 8)
    - Z.P. Townsend 1860 (Box 8)
    - James L. Tredway 1888-1889 (Box 8)
    - A.M. Trible 1858-1867 (Box 8)
    - Trible & Preston 1868-1872 (Box 8)
    - [James?] A. Trimble 1884 (Box 8)
    - James J.A. Trotter 1858, 1860 (Box 8)
    - Nicholas K. Trout 1857-1859 (Box 8)
    - S.G. Tucker 1856 (Box 8)
    - William A. Turner 1853-1861 (Box 8)
    - W.B. Turner 1845 (Box 8)
    - W.H. Tyler 1852 (Box 8)
    - G.W. Trueheart 1854 (Box 8)
    - University Publishing Company 1871 (Box 8)
    - John W. Utley 1870 (Box 8)
    - B.S. Vawter 1874 (Box 8)
    - B.P. Vawter 1874 (Box 8)
    - Victor & Ambler 1868, 1870 (Box 8)
    - M.D. Vines 1859-1860 (Box 8)
    - Virginia State Democratic Committee 1899-1913 (Box 8)
    - A. Waddill 1859, 1867 (Box 8)
    - Ben M. Wailes n.d. (Box 8)
    - Thomas D. Walford 1854 (Box 8)
    - E.R. Walker 1867 (Box 8)
    - Elijah R. Walker 1866 (Box 8)
    - James A. Walker 1857-1877 (Box 8)
    - John P. Wallace 1866 (Box 8)
    - Jacob Warwick 1867 (Box 8)
    - John W. Warwick 1857 (Box 8)
    - Joseph Washburn 1826 (Box 8)
    - Washington and Lee University 1888-1889 (Box 8)
    - George Waters 1893 (Box 8)
    - C.R. Watson 1855 (Box 8)
    - J.B. Watts 1849-1861 (Box 8)
    - William H. Watts 1866 (Box 8)
    - J. Wayt 1859 (Box 8)
    - A. Weil 1869 (Box 8)
    - J.H. Wells (Box 8)
    - A.F. Wherther 1861 (Box 8)
    - J.F.J. White n.d. (Box 8)
    - S.C. White 1895 (Box 8)
    - Millie Whitehead n.d. (Box 8)
    - Milton Whitney 1868 (Box 8)
    - W.L. Withers 1871 (Box 8)
    - William M. Withers 1867 (Box 8)
    - William Withrow, Jr. 1860-1869 (Box 8)
    - Edward Williams 1870 (Box 8)
    - Mary Williams n.d. (Box 8)
    - Williams, Peters & Company 1860 (Box 8)
    - E.F. Wills 1860 (Box 8)
    - P.E. Wilson 1871-1872 (Box 8)
    - D.J. Wood 1872 (Box 8)
    - Drury Wood 1870 (Box 8)
    - James H. Wood 1867 (Box 8)
    - Richard Wood 1869-1870 (Box 8)
    - Th. Wood 1858 (Box 8)
    - Edgar Woods 1867 (Box 8)
    - George M. and S. Jane Woods 1853-1872 (Box 8)
    - J. Warwick Woods 1860 (Box 8)
    - James Woodhouse 1854 (Box 8)
    - J.N. Woodward 1861 (Box 8)
    - Daniel L. Wright 1852, 1854 (Box 8)
    - Robert Whitehead 1846-1887 (Box 8)
    - Dr. Alexander F. Wills 1852-1861 (Box 9)
    - James L. Wills 1849-1870 (Box 9)
    - Wills Family 1845-1902, n.d. (Box 9)
    - X, Y, Z 1859, 1876 (Box 9)
    - Unidentified 1842-1901 (Box 9)
  - Financial and Legal Papers 1767-1911, n.d. (Box 9-17)
    1767-1814 (5 folders), 1815-1849 (7 folders), 1850-1853 September (7 folders), 1853 October-1856 (7 folders), 1857-1861 (8 folders), 1862-1870 (7 folders), 1871-1876 (9 folders), 1877-1911, n.d. (7 folders), n.d. (3 folders), 1798-1813 (Expense and Memoranda Book of [the Reverend John McCue])
    chronological
  - Genealogy 1845-1896, n.d. (Box 17)
    The McCues of the Old Dominion, 1650-1912, 1912
  - Legal Case Notes 1834-1888, n.d. (Box 18)
    1834-1888, n.d. (3 folders)
    ca. 1841-1848 (Hawes Coleman Estate)
    1874-1878 (re Lands of Colonel A.W. Harmon)
  - Marriage Licenses 1801-1818 (Box 18)
    chiefly Augusta County, Virginia
  - Miscellaneous 1777, 1845-1875, 1884 (Box 18)
    including the Oath of Allegiance of John McCue
  - Photographs 1873, n.d. (Box 18)
    including Mr. and Mrs. J.W. McCue; a stereoscopic view of 24 South Broad Street, [Savannah, Georgia]; and the residence of Thomas Barry, Hillsboro, Ohio; the rest are unidentified
  - Political Papers 1827-1829, 1861-1905 (Box 18)
    Includes election returns; the resolution of John H. Mc Cue re secession
    John H. Mc Cue's letter to the editor re African-American suffrage
    the Nelson County meeting re Andrew Jackson
- Series II: McCue Family Notebooks and Bound Volumes (Box 19 - M-27)
  - School Notebooks, etc., of C. Purcell McCue, Jr.
    - Booklets - Agribusiness 1937-1939 (Box 19)
    - Booklets - Farm Shop 1941, n.d. (Box 19)
    - Booklets - Miscellaneous 1937-1942 (Box 19)
    - Booklets - Supervised Farm Practice 1935-1941, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Booklets - Teacher Training 1932-1942, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Agribusiness 1938-1940, n.d., 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Biology 1938-1939, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Botany 1937-1941, n.d., 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Chemistry 1937-1940, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Chemistry 1937-1940, n.d. (Box 21)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Farming 1939-1942, n.d. (Box 21)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Farming - Farm Management 1938-1942, n.d., 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Future Farmers of America 1931-1942, n.d. (Carton 21)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Horticulture 1937-1940, n.d., 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Military 1940 (Box 22)
      Anti-Aircraft Artillery School, Camp Davis, N.C. of Lt. Charles P. McCue
    - Class work and Notebooks - Military 1944 (Box 22)
      Anti-Aircraft Replacement Training Center, Camp Stewart, Georgia of Lt. Charles P. McCue
    - Class work and Notebooks - Military ca. 1940-1943 (Box 23)
      Chemical Warfare and Military History of Lt. Charles P. McCue
    - Class work and Notebooks - Military 1938-1940 (Box 23)
      Reserve Officer Training Corps of Lt. Charles P. McCue
    - Class work and Notebooks - Miscellaneous 1939-1942, n.d., 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Teaching - Farm Shop 1936-1943, n.d., 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Teaching - Supervised Practice 1937-1943, n.d., 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Teaching - Supervised Practice - Study Calendars and Lesson Plans 1936-1942, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Teaching - Supervised Practice - Study Questions n.d. (Box 24)
    - Class work and Notebooks - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Christian Associations 1939-1942 (Box 24)
    - Notebook 1871-1872, bound volume (Box 24)
      re Physiology and Acoustics belonging to Lucien Guy Heneberger
    - Notebook ca. 1895, bound volume (Box 24)
      re Shakespeare belonging to Fannie M. Kyle
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 24)
      re Elizabethan Poets and Dramatists belonging to Fannie M. Kyle
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 24)
      re English Synonyms belonging to Fannie M. Kyle
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 24)
      re Literary Chronology belonging to Fannie M. Kyle
    - Notebook 1872, bound volume (Box 25)
      re [Anatomy?] belonging to Massie L. McCue
    - Notebook 1871-1872, bound volume (Box 25)
      re Physiology, Anatomy belonging to Massie L. McCue
    - Notebook [1872]-1873, bound volume (Box 25)
      re [Chemistry?] belonging to Massie L. McCue
    - Notebook 1871-[1872], bound volume (Box 25)
      re Chemistry belonging to Massie L. McCue
    - Notebook 1873, bound volume (Box 25)
      re Materia Medica belonging to Massie L. McCue
    - Notebook 1891-1892, bound volume (Othertype 25)
      re [Medicine ?] belonging to Massie L. McCue
    - Notebook ca. 1890, bound volume (Othertype 25)
      re [Biology, Medicine] belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 25)
      re Inorganic Chemistry belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 25)
      re French and Histology belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 25)
      re German belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)
      re Latin, Physics, Psychology belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)
      re Latin belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)
      re Pathology belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)
      re Pharmacy, Materia Medica belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Othertype 26)
      re Philosophy belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)
      re Physics, Chemistry Physics belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook 1884, bound volume (Box 26)
      re Physiology belonging to McDaniel Purcell
    - Notebook n.d., bound volume (Box 26)